(Q11（单选）) ⭐ Hello, I'm... —— 你好，我是……
⭐ archaeologist —— 考古学家｜investigate a site —— 调查一个遗址｜one of + 复数名词 —— ……之一
⭐ the third summer for... —— ……开展的第三个夏天｜dig —— 挖掘｜volunteer —— 志愿者
⭐ full-time archaeologist —— 全职考古学家｜town council —— 市议会｜be asked to do sth —— 被邀请/要求做某事｜set up projects —— 建立项目｜up and down the country —— 全国各地
⭐ as you can see —— 正如你所看到的｜be next to... —— 在……旁边｜let sb do sth —— 允许某人做某事｜facilities —— 设施
⭐ get to where we are today —— 发展到今天这个阶段
⭐ archaeology project —— 考古项目｜ancient object —— 古代物品｜in our case —— 在我们的情况下
⭐ metal detector —— 金属探测器｜buried in the ground —— 埋在地下｜uncover —— 发现；揭露｜dig tunnels —— 挖洞穴
⭐ walker —— 徒步者；散步的人｜wash away —— 冲走｜earth and sand —— 泥土和沙子
⭐ hit the news —— 登上新闻｜amateur historian —— 业余历史学家｜contact sb —— 联系某人｜there had been... —— 曾经存在过……
⭐ by chance —— 偶然地｜old maps and documents —— 老地图和文件｜ruined buildings —— 废弃建筑；建筑遗迹｜outer stone walls —— 外部石墙
⭐ be onto something —— 找到了重要线索；发现了有价值的东西
⭐ over the three summers —— 在三个夏天期间｜the remains of... —— ……的遗迹｜more than you can count —— 数不清的
⭐ expect to do sth —— 预计做某事｜brooch —— 胸针｜jewellery —— 珠宝｜such items —— 这样的物品
⭐ once lived here —— 曾经住在这里｜be skilled at doing sth —— 擅长做某事｜make tools from... —— 用……制作工具
⭐ besides... —— 除了……｜evidence of... —— ……的证据｜human activity —— 人类活动｜so far —— 到目前为止｜field system —— 农田系统
⭐ at one point —— 曾经；某个时候｜turn out to be... —— 结果证明是……
⭐ end soon —— 很快结束｜be back —— 回来
⭐ in the meantime —— 与此同时｜put on —— 举办；组织｜a series of... —— 一系列……｜guided tour —— 导览参观
⭐ documentary —— 纪录片
⭐ suggest —— 暗示；提到｜for sure —— 确定地
(Q17（地图）) ⭐ make sure... —— 确保……｜keep to the paths —— 沿着道路走
⭐ highlights of... —— ……的亮点｜if you like —— 如果你愿意这样说的话
⭐ take a look at... —— 看一下……｜present location —— 当前位置｜be marked —— 被标记
⭐ identify —— 确认；识别｜foundation —— 地基
⭐ a team of divers —— 一队潜水员｜search for... —— 寻找……
⭐ to reach... —— 为了到达……｜go straight on —— 直走｜bend to the left —— 向左弯
⭐ track —— 小路｜lead off to... —— 分叉通向……
⭐ follow that —— 沿着那条路走｜where... —— ……所在的位置
(Q18) ⭐ might be interested to do sth —— 可能会对做某事感兴趣
⭐ northwest corner —— 西北角
⭐ date to... —— 追溯到……｜the time of... —— ……时期
⭐ oyster shells —— 牡蛎壳｜assume —— 假设；认为｜be thrown from... —— 被从……扔出
(Q19) ⭐ excavate —— 挖掘｜uncover —— 发现
⭐ row of... —— 一排……｜post hole —— 柱洞｜support a roof —— 支撑屋顶
⭐ structure —— 建筑结构｜current excavation area —— 当前挖掘区域
(Q20) ⭐ discover —— 发现｜fish pond —— 鱼塘
⭐ beside —— 在……旁边
⭐ further away —— 更远｜it's possible that... —— 有可能……
⭐ to get there from here —— 从这里到那里｜turn right at... —— 在……右转｜information board —— 信息牌｜follow the path —— 沿路走
⭐ come out of... —— 从……出来
⭐ go too far —— 走过头
⭐ Does anyone...? —— 有人……吗？